You have something I want.
It means more to me
than you will ever know.
The Child is gone.
Until he is returned to you safely,
we are in your debt.
Cara Dune,
Marshal of the New Republic.
I need you to locate someone
in the prison registry.
Ex-Imperial sharpshooter,
last name Mayfeld.
Serving 50 years
in the Karthon Chop Fields.
Accessory to the death
of a New Republic officer.
Get that blaster out of my face, Mando!
Realize
what you'll bring down on us?
You think I care about that?
- Get that blaster out of my face.
- I can't do that.
Crazy Twi.
No!
Inmate three-four-six-six-seven.
What? What?
Inmate three-four-six-six-seven,
descend and receive new instructions.
Can't you see I'm busy?
Inmate three-four-six-six-seven,
please salute Marshal Dune.
I remand prisoner number
three-four-six-six-seven to my custody.
Affirmative.
Inmate three-four-six-six-seven,
please follow Marshal Dune to transport.
-Somebody gonna tell me what's going on?
-Let's go! I've got a job for you.
Inmate three-four-six-six-seven,
please follow Marshal Dune.
Wait, where is she takin' me?
Inmate three-four-six-six-seven,
you have three seconds
to comply with your new directive.
Okay! All right, all right.
Hey!
You gonna tell me where you're takin' me?
Hello?
I mean, it's a common courtesy,
a common courtesy to tell somebody
where it is that you're takin' 'em.
I don't think
that's so hard to ask, do you?
You know, for a second,
I thought you were this other guy.
Mayfeld.
Hey, Mando.
Long time.
What, you came here to kill me?
All you need to know is I bent
a lot of rules to bring you along.
Why am I so lucky?
Because you're Imperial.
Hey, that was a long time ago, all right?
You still know
your Imperial clearances
and protocols, don't you?
We need coordinates
for Moff Gideon's cruiser.
Moff Gideon?
Yeah, forget it.
Just take me back to the scrapyard.
I'm not doin' that.
They have his kid.
The little green guy?
Yeah, "The little green guy."
So...
I help you guys get him back,
you guys let me go?
That's not how this works.
Well, then what's in it for me?
You get a better view.
All right, but here's the thing.
I can't get those coordinates
unless I have access
to an internal Imperial terminal.
I believe there's one on Morak.
Morak?
There's nothing on Morak.
It's a secret Imperial mining hub, okay?
If you can get me in there,
I can get you the coordinates.
Fett,
punch in the coordinates to Morak.
Copy that.
I did an initial scan of the planet.
This is what you're talkin' about, right?
Yeah, that's the refinery right there.
Wonder what they're refining in there.
Looks like rhydonium.
Highly volatile and explosive.
Yeah, kinda like this one.
They have anti-aircraft cannons
protecting it.
And a platoon of security forces.
So we go in quiet.
Let's go get a closer look.
I'm not gonna need long inside,
so once I get the coordinates, you guys
gotta get me the hell out of there.
You get to the roof.
I'll drop in and pull you out.
All right. Mayfeld and I will swap out
for the drivers in the tunnel.
As much as I'd like to take a road trip
with Rebel-dropper here,
that's not gonna work.
Yeah? Why's that?
Well, because these Remnant bases
are set up and run by ex-ISB.
If you get scanned
and your genetic signature
shows up on any New Republic register,
you're gonna be detected,
and it's guns out.
You sure do know
a lot about Imperial Remnants.
If you wanna accuse me of something,
then just say it.
We don't have time.
Fennec will go.
No, I'm wanted by the ISB.
I'll trip the alarm, too.
Fett?
Let's just say
they might recognize my face.
Great, so it's me goin' in alone.
No way.
The minute he gets inside,
he'll tip 'em off. He'll be a hero.
Hey. This wasn't my idea.
I'm doin' you guys a favor.
Deal's off.
I'm takin' him back.
I'll go.
Hey, buddy,
I might be good at fast-talking,
but I don't think I can explain away
a guy in a Mando suit to Imperial guards.
So, unless
you're gonna take off that helmet,
it's gonna be me goin' in alone.
Or say goodbye
to your little green friend.
You're not going alone.
I'm coming with you.
But I won't be showing my face.
Refinery, this is Juggernaut Five
entering tunnel T-12.
Copy that.
Juggernaut Four has reached
the north exit. You're all clear.
What the...
My God, this guy reeked.
His gloves are still wet.
Look at this.
The shame.
Now, that right there
is worth the price of admission.
Wish I could say it looked good on you,
but I'd be lying.
Just make sure
you take out the rooftop gunners,
or we're never getting out of here.
We got you.
Take care of this. Keep it safe.
I will.
Hey, guys. Still on the clock.
What would they say on Mandalore?
It's a shame
you're not comin' along with us.
You got such a sunny disposition.
Can't imagine how much fun you are
in one of these.
What's goin' on here?
Power coil, motivator...
There we...
There we go. There we go!
And we are off.
Hey, how's it feel?
I mean, c'mon, man,
you still get to wear a helmet, right?
All right, you know what?
I'm takin' this thing off.
I can't see anything.
I don't know
how you people wear those things.
And by "you people,"
I do mean Mandalorians.
Phase one, complete. We're in.
Copy. Standing by.
Feels better when it's off.
Juggernaut Four,
you're running hot.
Be sure to watch
your cargo heat limits and speed.
Copy that, Three. We hit
a couple bumps. Thanks for the heads-up.
Don't worry about the rhydonium.
As long as you drive steady,
you'll get us to the refinery.
Go, go!
- Out of the road. Go!
- Get to safety!
Yeah. Empire, New Republic.
It's all the same to these people.
Invaders on their land is all we are.
I'm just sayin',
somewhere someone in this galaxy
is ruling and others are being ruled.
I mean, look at your race.
Do you think all those people
that died in wars fought by Mandalorians
actually had a choice?
So how are they any different
than the Empire?
If you were born on Mandalore,
you believe one thing,
if you're born on Alderaan,
you believe somethin' else.
But guess what?
Neither one of 'em exist anymore.
Hey, I'm just a realist.
I'm a survivor, just like you.
Let's get one thing straight.
You and I are nothing alike.
I don't know. Seems to me like your rules
start to change when you get desperate.
I mean, look at ya.
You said
you couldn't take your helmet off,
and now you got a stormtrooper one on,
so what's the rule?
Is it that you can't take off your
Mando helmet, or you can't show your face?
'Cause there is a difference.
Look, I'm just sayin', we're all the same.
Everybody's got their lines
they don't cross until things get messy.
As far as I'm concerned,
if you can make it through your day
and still sleep at night,
you're doin' better than most.
Control, this is Juggernaut Three.
We're comin' up
on some route interference.
- Control, control!
- We need a new...
What was that?
Please stand by for reroute.
Juggernaut Four has been destroyed.
"Destroyed"?
The rhydonium is still stable.
Juggernaut Five,
maintain speed and course.
Proceed with caution.
-Re-routing course, stand by.
-"Proceed with caution"? Is she serious?
Control,
this is Juggernaut Three. Requesting...
Abort! Abort!
What the hell was that?
Pirates. Keep driving.
I'll take care of it.
Are you seriously
shooting a blaster near rhydonium?
They've thermal detonators.
- Terrific.
- Just keep it steady.
Get these guys off us!
Get 'em off us!
-They're trying to blow the rhydonium.
-You think?
You should've left me in prison!
Mayfeld! Pick it up. Drive faster!
I don't think faster's a good idea!
What are you doing?
Mando, I gotta stop.
I can't cross at this speed.
Whoo!
Go! Go!
Stay on high alert!
Fire! On your right!
Never thought you'd be happy
to see stormtroopers.
Here they are.
They made it.
Yes!
Glory of the Empire!
There we go!
Okay. All we gotta do is find a terminal.
Ya did it!
Bringing glory to the Empire!
It's probably in the officers' mess.
I can't believe they pulled that off.
There it is.
- Okay.
- Good luck.
- I can't go in there.
- Why not?
-That's Valin Hess.
-Who?
It's Valin Hess.
I used to serve under him.
- Will he recognize you?
- I don't know.
I was just a field operative,
but I'm not takin' the chance. It's over.
Let's just do this quick
and we can get out of here.
I can't do it, okay?
We have to abort. I'm sorry.
No. I can't.
If we don't get those coordinates,
I'll lose the kid forever.
-Give me the data stick.
-It's not gonna work.
In order to access the network,
the terminal has to scan your face.
Let's go.
Give it to me.
Error, error. Facial scan incomplete.
Ten seconds to system shutdown.
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six,
five, four, three, two...
Facial scan complete.
Trooper!
Hey, trooper.
Pay attention
when a superior addresses you.
What's your designation?
Transport crew.
What?
My designation is transport copilot.
No, son.
What's your TK number?
My TK number is...
This is my Commanding Officer
TK-593, sir.
I'm Imperial Combat Assault Transport
Lieutenant TK-111, sir.
I'm afraid you'll have to
speak up to him a little bit
since his vessel lost pressure in Taanab.
What's your name, Officer?
We just call him Brown Eyes.
Isn't that right, Officer?
Let's go fill out those TPS reports,
so we can go recharge the power coils.
You're not dismissed.
You the tank troopers
that delivered the shipment of rhydonium?
-Yes, sir.
Well, you two managed to be the only
transport today to deliver their shipment.
Come with me?
Let's get a drink, Brown Eyes.
We'll have to take out those cannons
if Boba's gonna get close enough
to lift 'em outta there.
Shouldn't be a problem.
You concentrate on the troopers,
I'll take the cannons.
I wonder what's takin' them so long.
So what shall we toast to, boys?
I can blather on about
"To health" or "To success,"
but I'd like to do
somethin' a little less rote.
Where you from, Brown Eyes?
How 'bout a toast to Operation Cinder?
Now there's a man who knows his history.
No, I don't just know it. I lived it.
I was in Burnin Konn.
Burnin Konn?
That was a hard day.
I had to make many unpleasant decisions.
Yes, you did.
Entire city gone in moments,
along with everybody in it.
We lost our whole division that day.
Man, that was like 5-10,000 people.
Yep.
All heroes of the Empire.
Yeah.
And all dead.
Well, it's a small sacrifice
for the greater good, son.
Depends on who you ask, don't you think?
What you gettin' at, trooper?
All those people, the ones who died,
was it good for them?
Their families?
The guys I served with?
Civilians, those poor mud scuffers,
died defendin' their homes,
fighting for freedom.
Was it good for 'em?
But we've outlasted them, son.
They're eatin' themselves alive.
The New Republic is in complete disarray,
and we grow stronger.
You see,
with the rhydonium you've delivered,
we can create havoc that's gonna make
Burnin Konn just pale by comparison.
And then they're gonna
turn to us once again.
You see, boys,
everybody thinks they want freedom,
but what they really want is order.
And when they realize that,
they're gonna welcome us back
with open arms.
To the Empire.
You did what you had to do.
I never saw your face.
Security to main commons.
This way!
We need support at the mess hall.
Ready? Go!
Hold it right there!
South wall, halfway up.
Got 'em.
We're on. Start your run.
On my way.
Three shooters, top deck.
Got 'em.
- Let's move.
- The hell you think I'm doin'?
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Hand me that cycler rifle.
Nice shot.
We all need to sleep at night.
We got company.
Hang on.
Well, looks like
it's back to the scrap heap.
Thank you for helping.
Yeah.
Good luck gettin' your kid back.
All right, Officer,
take me back.
That was some nice shootin' back there.
You saw that?
Yeah, that,
that wasn't part of the plan.
I was just gettin' some stuff
off my chest.
You know, it's too bad Mayfeld
didn't make it out alive back there.
Yeah, too bad.
What are you talkin' about?
Looked to me like prisoner number
three-four-six-six-seven
died in the refinery explosion on Morak.
Does that mean I can go?
'Cause I will.
All right.
Okay.
You get the coordinates on Moff Gideon?
We did.
What's our next move?
Sir...
You should see this.
Moff Gideon.
You have something I want.
You may think you have some idea
what you are in possession of,
but you do not.
Soon, he will be back with me.
He means more to me
than you will ever know.